Mss.B.Sa95.g
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Th[omas] Say, Philadelphia, June 22, 1822; 10x8; Férusac, André-Etienne-Just-Pascal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. In French. (see Thomas Say. correspondence.) Mollusks. Refers to Lesueur. Moths.
  - Letter to Thomas Say, New Harmony, July 6, [1822?]; 10-1/4x8; Férusac, André-Etienne-Just-Pascal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, A.L. 4p.and add. In French. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Entomology. Snails. Mollusks. Concerning Lesueur and the APS.
  - Letter to [Baron de Férussac], June 5, 1824; 7-1/4x5-1/4; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    Philadelphia, A.L. 4p. Draft. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Concerning shells and natural history. Moths.
  - Letter to [Thomas Say], Oct. 15, 1824; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bonaparte, Charles Lucian, p, 1803-1857
    Point Breeze, A.L.S. 2p. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Asks him to correct some of his errors. American fishes and snails.
  - Letter to [Thomas Say], Nov. 3, 1824; 10x8; Férusac, André-Etienne-Just-Pascal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, L.S. 4p. In French. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Insects and mollusks. Inquires of Rafinesque and his publications. Natural history.
  - Letter to Baron de Férussac, May (?), 1825; 8x3-1/4; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    A.L.S.with initials. 2p. Draft. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Entomology and mollusks. Concerning his publications on natural history. Refers to the Academy of natural sciences Refers to Dejean.
  - Letter to [Thomas Say], Sept., 1825; 10x8; Dejean, Pierre François Auguste, comte, 1780-1845
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Concerning publications. Marine fauna.
  - Letter to Jacob Gilliams, Philadelphia, June 7, 1827; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Say papers.) Are raising silk-worms. Natural history. Concerning his Entomology. Concerning Maclure. Friendly letter. Originally housed at B Sa95.g.4
  - Letter to [Baron de Férussac?], Nov.1, 1827; 6-1/4x3-1/2; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, A.L. 2p. Draft. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Received his long delayed letter. Moths.
  - Letter to Jacob Gilliams, Philadelphia, Sept. 25, 1828; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p.and add.: "per Mr Maclure" (see Say papers.) Entomology. Concerning entomological publications for the ANS. Friendly letter. Originally housed at B Sa95.g.4
  - Letter to [Jacob Gilliams], Dec. 25, 1828; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Photo.of A.L. 2p. Incomplete. (see Say papers.) His interest in the natural history of the U.S. His American entomology. Refers to the ANS, Maclure, etc. Originally housed at B Sa95.g.4
  - Letter to Jacob Gilliams, Philadelphia, Feb. 4, 182[9?]; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Photo.of A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Say papers.) Publications. Concerning shells. Friendly letter. Refers to Maclure. Originally housed at B Sa95.g.4
  - Letter to Jacob Gilliams, Philadelphia, June 1, 1829; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Say papers.) Sends colored plates for his publication..Originally housed at B Sa95.g.4
  - Letter to [Charles Wilkins Short], Jan. 21, 1831; 11x8-1/2; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    Typed transcript copy from the original in the possession of the Filson Club. Presented to the Society by Mrs. Effie Cameron James, June 1955.
    New Harmony, Ind., Typed L. 1p. (see Say papers.) Accounts for three issues of American Conchology sent to him, Eaton and Transylvania. Refers to Maclure. Previously housed at B Sa95.g.3 (No. 1).
  - Letter to [Charles Wilkins Short], March 1, 1831; 11x8-1/2; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Ind., Typed L. 1p. (see Say papers.) Introduces William Bennett, "a pupil of Mr. Maclure's". Concerning plants. Previously housed at B Sa95.g.3 (No.2).
  - Letter to [Charles Wilkins Short], July 19, 1831; 11x8-1/2; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Ind., Typed L. 4p. (see Say papers.) Description of shells printed with few changed: Transylvania Journal of Medicine and the Associate Sciences,IV,no.IV,(1831) 525-527. Previously housed at B Sa95.g.3 (No. 3)
  - Letter to [Charles Wilkins Short], Jan. 14, 1832; 11x8-1/2; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, Typed L. 2p. (see Say papers.) Printed in part: Filson Club History Quarterly, XII (1938), 207. Previously hourse at B Sa95.g.3 (No.4)
  - Letter to Benjamin Say, Aug. 23, 1832; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    Originally housed at B Sa9.g.5
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s Say, New Harmony, Nov. 17, Nov. 29, 1832; 10x7-3/4; Peter, Robert, 1805-1894
    Lexington, Ky., A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Concerning the purchase of his publication on shells. Mollusks.
  - Letter to [Charles Wilkins Short], March 5, 1833; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    Typed copy from the originals in the possession of the Filson Club; presented to the Soceity by Mrs. Effie Cameron James, June 1955; previously housed at B Sa95.g.3 (No.5).
  - Letter to Dr. C[harles] W[ilkins] Short, June 11, 1834; 11x8-1/2; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    New Harmony, Ind., Typed L. 1p.with P.S.by Thomas Say. Copy. (see Say papers.) Sends seeds collected by Prince Maximilian Nuewied. Previously housed at B Sa95.g.3 (No.6).
  - Letter to [Thomas Say], Sept. 10, 1834; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Férusac, André-Etienne-Just-Pascal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Shells.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, June 25, 1860; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    Newburgh, A.L.S. 11p. (see Say papers.) Concerning Mr. Ord's memoir on Thomas Say. Her formal reply to it. This item was located in and removed, Dec. 1960 from v. 1: Say. Complete Writings...Entomology...ed.by J.L.LeConte. Originally housed at B Sa95.g.2
  - Letter to Mrs. [Lucy Way Sistaire] Say, June 28, 1860; 8-1/4x5; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Philadelphia, A.L. 2p. (see Say Papers.) Concerning George Ord's memoir on Thomas Say. Refers to the APS. This item was located in and removed, Dec. 1960 from v.1: Say. Complete Writings...Entomology...ed.by J.L.LeConte. Originally housed at B Sa95.g.1
  - Letter to Arthur F. Gray, Danversport, Mass., Jan. 6, 1883; 8x5; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    A.L.S. 4p.and add. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Gives him drawings of shells used for Say's work on U.S. mollusks. Concerning Thomas Say. Refers to the Academy of natural sciences.
  - Letter to Mrs. Lucy W. Say, Jan. 11, 1883; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Gray, Arthur F.
    Danversport, Mass., L. 3p. Copy. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Thanks for drawings of shells. Concerning Thomas Say. Mollusks.
  - Letter to A[rthur] F. Gray, Jan. 16, [1883]; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Sends parcel containing sketches of shells.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Lucy W.] Say, Jan. 20, 1883; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Gray, Arthur F.
    Danversport, Mass., L. 1p. Copy. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Thanks for plates and Thomas Say's letters.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Lucy Way] Say, Feb. 6, 1883; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Gray, Arthur F.
    Cincinnati, L. 3p. Copy. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Concerning shells and errors made by Isaac Lea. Arranging her plates as they appeared in American Conchology. Refers to Bonaparte and Lesueur.
  - Letter to Mr. [Arthur F.] Gray, Feb. 13, 1883; 8x5; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Concerning her knowledge of natural science. Concerning T.Say and Bonaparte. Refers to the Academy of natural sciences and Lesueur.
  - Letter to Arthur F. Gray,Cincinnati, March 8, 1883; 8x5; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    Staten Island, A.L.S. 6p.and add. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Has sent photograph of herself. Her knowledge of natural history based on her husband's teachings. Refers to Lea.
  - Letter to Arthur F. Gray, Danversport, Mass., April 24, 1883; 8x5; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    Staten Island, A.L.S. 4p.and add. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Describes her life. Has publication by William D. Hartman given her by Isaac Lea.
  - Letter to Arthur F. Gray, Danversport, Mass., May 15, 1883; 8x5; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    Staten Island, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Gives directions to her home for him to visit her.
  - Letter to [Baron de] Férusac., undated; 8x4-1/2; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    A.L. 4p.,end.: "To the Baron de Férussac. first Letter." Draft. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.) Concerning shells.
  - Biographical notes about Thomas Say, 1787-1834, undated
    Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
  - Miscellaneous notes on conchology, etc., 1827; July 1824;July 11, 1833-undated; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    A.D. 92 items (one of which is a notebook entitled "Mammalia", consisting of 6p.) Various sizes. (see Thomas Say. Correspondence.)
  - Memorandum pertaining to Thomas Say-Charles Wilkins Short correspondence, June, 1955; 11x8-1/2; James, Mary Effie Cameron
    Typed D. 1p. (see Say papers.); 0riginally housed at B Sa95.g.3 (no.7)
- Graphics, undated; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
  Series II. Graphics
  Engraver's proofs used as plates for The Complete Writings of Thomas Say on the Conchology of the United States A.D. 47 items, Various sizes. (see Thomas Say. Collection...) [not individually descibed]; Includes numbered Plates, 3, 7, 9, 13-14, 19, 21-34, 36-40, 42-44, 46-50, 53-55, 57-61, 63, 66, 68; Plates 35 and 51 are folio and housed separately. Some plates/drawings are accompanied by color slides of same. Available online in Open Library at: http://www.archive.org/stream/americanconcholo00sayt#page/n25/mode/2up
  - Various drawings executed by Mrs. Lucy W. Say as yet unpublished, undated; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    Unpublished drawings of shells, Nos. 1-11.